Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
♪In the old house, a light breeze blows♪
♪في البيت القديم، تهب نسمة خفيفة♪
♪Carrying a wisp of floral fragrance♪
♪تحمل خصلة من العطر الزهري♪
♪You left in such haste, without hesitation♪
♪لقد غادرت على عجل، دون تردد♪
♪Before I could even feel the joy♪
♪قبل أن أشعر بالفرح♪
♪I dared not write a single word♪
♪لم أجرؤ على كتابة كلمة واحدة♪
♪Afraid it would give my heart away♪
♪أخشى أن يكشف قلبي♪
♪Leaving behind a foolish soul in loneliness♪
♪ترك وراءه روحًا حمقاء في الوحدة♪
♪The world grows old♪
♪العالم يشيخ♪
♪Time slips by like a blade♪
♪يمر الوقت مثل الشفرة♪
♪Through every day and night as I wait for the flowers to bloom♪
♪في كل يوم وليلة وأنا أنتظر الزهور لتتفتح♪
♪It feels as though a thousand years never passed♪
♪أشعر وكأن ألف عام لم تمر أبدًا♪
♪The wind lets petals fall into your palm♪
♪الريح تجعل البتلات تسقط في راحة يدك♪
♪Love makes us foolish, lost in endless memories♪
♪الحب يجعلنا حمقى، ضائعين في ذكريات لا نهاية لها♪
♪No one cares about our story♪
♪لا أحد يهتم بقصتنا♪
♪Slowly fading away♪
♪تتلاشى ببطء♪
♪Flowers bloom in snow, brief as life itself♪
♪تزهر الزهور في الثلج، قصيرة مثل الحياة نفسها♪
♪So many poems through the ages speak of♪
♪تتحدث العديد من القصائد عبر العصور عن♪
♪Love and hatred, partings and vows of the past♪
♪الحب والكراهية، الفراق وعهود الماضي♪
♪Had we never crossed paths in this lifetime♪
♪لو لم نلتقي قط في هذه الحياة♪
♪Nothing could separate us, even if we were oceans apart♪
♪لا شيء يمكن أن يفصلنا، حتى لو كنا بعيدين عن بعضنا البعض بالمحيطات♪
=The Princess Decree=
=مرسوم الأميرة=
=Episode 8=
=الحلقة 8=
General Gan, what does this mean?
السيد الجنرال جان ماذا يعني هذا؟
The Vice Minister of Revenue position has been vacant for long.
ظل منصب نائب وزير الإيرادات شاغرًا لفترة طويلة.
I
أنا
have found a suitable candidate.
لقد وجدت مرشحًا مناسبًا.
What do you
ما يفعله لك
think?
يفكر؟
Vice Minister Wang.
نائب الوزير وانغ.
You couldn't fit in among the civil ministers
لم يكن بإمكانك أن تتأقلم مع الوزراء المدنيين
and quickly found a new patron.
وسرعان ما وجدت راعيًا جديدًا.
How clever.
كم هو ذكي.
A wise man adapts to the times.
الرجل الحكيم يتكيف مع العصر.
You flatter me.
أنت تملقني.
It's a pity
إنه لأمر مؤسف
that I don't like him.
أنني لا أحبه.
Why?
لماذا؟
He offended me.
لقد أساء إلي.
Didn't you know?
ألم تعلم؟
Please calm down.
من فضلك اهدأ.
Just because he insulted Li Yuanze?
فقط لأنه أهان لي يوانزي؟
I won't let anyone,
لن اسمح لأحد
even ordinary people,
حتى الناس العاديين،
question my things.
اسأل عن أغراضي.
You know this feeling
هل تعرف هذا الشعور؟
better than anyone.
أفضل من أي شخص.
Right?
يمين؟
But
لكن
Li Yuanze is no ordinary man.
لي يوانزي ليس رجلاً عاديًا.
You let this beast out of the cage
لقد تركت هذا الوحش خارج القفص
and ruined my plans.
ودمرت خططي.
Shouldn't you compensate me?
ألا يجب عليك تعويضي؟
If not for your scheme to sow discord,
إن لم يكن مخططك هو بث الفتنة،
he wouldn't have emerged so fast.
لم يكن ليخرج بهذه السرعة.
What do you really want?
ماذا تريد حقا؟
From the beginning,
من البداية،
all I want
كل ما أريده
is your support.
هو دعمك.
After all,
بعد كل شيء،
we are on the same path.
نحن على نفس المسار.
Don't you agree?
ألا توافق؟
Regarding the promotion of Vice Minister Wang
بخصوص ترقية نائب الوزير وانغ
to Minister of Revenue,
إلى وزير الإيرادات،
what are the ministers' opinions?
ما هي آراء الوزراء؟
Your Majesty.
جلالتك.
Vice Minister Wang has no experience
نائب الوزير وانغ ليس لديه أي خبرة
and may not even understand
وقد لا يفهم حتى
taxes or accounts.
الضرائب أو الحسابات.
How can someone who only seeks pleasure
فكيف يستطيع من لا يسعى إلا للمتعة أن
bear such a burden?
تحمل مثل هذا العبء؟
Once appointed,
بمجرد تعيينه،
it's chaos at best, and state affairs will be delayed at worst.
إنها حالة من الفوضى في أحسن الأحوال، وسوف تتأخر شؤون الدولة في أسوأ الأحوال.
Meanwhile, Official Lin has served in Ministry of Revenue for years
وفي الوقت نفسه، خدم المسؤول لين في وزارة الإيرادات لسنوات.
without a single mistake.
بدون خطأ واحد.
(Xiao Pingzhao, Emperor of Jing) Clearly, he should take the post.
(شياو بينغزهاو، إمبراطور جينغ) من الواضح أنه يجب أن يتولى المنصب.
Experience can always be gained.
يمكن اكتساب الخبرة دائمًا.
Official Zhang.
تشانغ الرسمي.
Were you born
هل ولدت؟
already knowing Confucian classics?
هل تعرف بالفعل الكلاسيكيات الكونفوشيوسية؟
Absurd.
سخيف.
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
Vice Minister Wang
نائب الوزير وانغ
is the most suitable candidate for Minister of Revenue.
هو المرشح الأنسب لمنصب وزير الإيرادات.
General Gan, you're wrong.
الجنرال جان، أنت مخطئ.
Civil officials' posts
وظائف المسؤولين المدنيين
cannot be arranged by generals.
لا يمكن ترتيبها من قبل الجنرالات.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
It's not up to them.
ليس الأمر متروك لهم.
Ridiculous.
سخيف.
Is that so?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Official Li.
لي الرسمي.
What if I insist on intervening?
ماذا لو أصررت على التدخل؟
General Gan is thoughtful.
الجنرال جان متفكر.
In my opinion,
في رأيي،
Vice Minister Wang is an excellent choice.
نائب الوزير وانغ هو خيار ممتاز.
Official Lin knows Ministry of Revenue well,
المسؤول لين يعرف وزارة الإيرادات جيدًا،
but he's old.
لكنه كبير في السن.
The Jing court needs new vigor.
تحتاج محكمة جينغ إلى قوة جديدة.
Princess Royal is wise.
الأميرة الملكية حكيمة.
- Princess Royal is wise.
- الأميرة الملكية حكيمة.
Official Li, what do you think?
المسؤول لي، ما رأيك؟
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Ministry of Revenue oversees household registration and finances.
تشرف وزارة الإيرادات على تسجيل الأسر والشؤون المالية.
It concerns the people, leaving no room for error.
فهو يهم الناس، ولا يترك مجالا للخطأ.
Moreover,
علاوة على ذلك،
the people's welfare concerns the state.
رفاهية الشعب من اختصاص الدولة.
I believe that even Princess Royal
أعتقد أن حتى الأميرة الملكية
has no right to intervene.
ليس له الحق في التدخل.
You look down on me.
أنت تنظر إليّ.
But what if I say
ولكن ماذا لو قلت
this is His Majesty's order?
هذا أمر جلالته؟
His Majesty?
صاحب الجلالة؟
His Majesty has entrusted me to fully handle this matter.
لقد أوكل إلي جلالته مهمة التعامل الكامل مع هذه المسألة.
Official Li, are you resisting the order?
السيد المسؤول لي، هل تقاوم الأمر؟
I dare not resist,
لا أجرؤ على المقاومة،
but I cannot bear to see
ولكنني لا أستطيع أن أتحمل رؤية
His Majesty deceived by traitors.
جلالته مخدوع من قبل الخونة.
Insolence!
وقاحة!
It seems
يبدو أنه
Official Li holds a grudge against me.
المسؤول لي يحمل ضغينة ضدي.
How about you explain in detail?
ماذا عن شرحك بالتفصيل؟
Don't jump to conclusions.
لا تقفز إلى الاستنتاجات.
Vice Minister Wang.
نائب الوزير وانغ.
(Ledgers of Year 35 of Jiande) Are you familiar with these ledgers?
(دفاتر السنة 35 من جيانده) هل أنت على دراية بهذه الدفاتر؟
Every sum you embezzled
كل مبلغ اختلسته
is traceable.
يمكن تتبعها.
Confess immediately!
اعترف فورًا!
Forgive me.
سامحني.
If you insist on shielding him,
إذا كنت تصر على حمايته،
I will report it at the cost of my life.
سأبلغ عن ذلك حتى لو كان الثمن حياتي.
I will question His Majesty
سأسأل جلالته
who allowed this rat
من سمح لهذا الفأر
to touch Ministry of Revenue?
للمس وزارة الإيرادات؟
You...
أنت...
- Please deal with Vice Minister Wang.
- من فضلك تعامل مع نائب الوزير وانغ.
Imprison him first. We'll discuss it later.
اسجنوه أولًا. سنناقش الأمر لاحقًا.
- Your Highness. - Yes.
- صاحب السمو. - نعم.
Your Highness, forgive me! Your Highness!
سموك، سامحني! سموك!
Li Yuanze.
لي يوانزي.
Just you wait.
فقط انتظر.
Victory and defeat are common in warfare.
النصر والهزيمة أمران شائعان في الحرب.
What's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Already losing your patience?
هل فقدت صبرك بالفعل؟
I believed
لقد اعتقدت
having you
وجودك
will make this a sure victory.
سيجعل هذا فوزا أكيدًا.
It seems
يبدو أنه
I overestimated you.
لقد بالغت في تقديرك.
Who said you lost?
من قال أنك خسرت؟
A fence-sitter like Vice Minister Wang
شخص متردد مثل نائب الوزير وانج
sways to
يتأرجح إلى
whoever benefits him.
من ينفعه.
A small punishment
عقوبة صغيرة
will teach him boundaries.
سوف يعلمه الحدود.
Once he suffers enough,
بمجرد أن يعاني بما فيه الكفاية،
we'll help him again.
سنساعده مرة أخرى.
Are you worried about
هل أنت قلق بشأن
not being able to train a loyal dog?
عدم القدرة على تدريب كلب مخلص؟
I
أنا
shall wait and see.
سوف ننتظر ونرى.
(Princess Royal Yong'an's Residence)
(مقر إقامة الأميرة الملكية يونغآن)
We can't keep a traitor like Vice Minister Wang.
لا يمكننا الاحتفاظ بخائن مثل نائب الوزير وانغ.
If he becomes Gan Sheng's lapdog in Ministry of Revenue,
إذا أصبح كلب جان شنغ في وزارة الإيرادات،
it will be disastrous.
سيكون الأمر كارثيا.
Fortunately, Official Li is in court today.
ولحسن الحظ فإن المسؤول لي موجود في المحكمة اليوم.
Originally,
أصلا،
I wanted to stabilize Gan Sheng
أردت أن أستقر في جان شنغ
before planning ahead.
قبل التخطيط للمستقبل.
Without him,
بدونه،
I can still devise a solution.
لا أزال أستطيع التوصل إلى حل.
What is it?
ما هذا؟
The solution?
الحل؟
Yuanze, what is it?
يوانزي، ما هذا؟
To resolve this,
لحل هذه المشكلة،
- there's only one way left. - There's only one way left.
- لم يتبق سوى طريق واحد.
And that's...
و هذا...
Act before Gan Sheng.
التصرف أمام جان شنغ.
- Kill him.
- اقتله.
Vice Minister Wang.
نائب الوزير وانغ.
You've disappointed me.
لقد خيبت ظني.
Official Li really has refined tastes.
لدى لي الرسمي ذوق راقي حقًا.
Strolling here at midnight.
المشي هنا في منتصف الليل.
Could it be
هل يمكن أن يكون
you came here
لقد أتيت إلى هنا
to pay respects to your mentor?
لتقديم الاحترام لمعلمك؟
I'll give you one last chance.
سأعطيك فرصة أخيرة.
Hand over the evidence of your collusion with Gan Sheng,
سلم الدليل على تواطؤك مع جان شنغ،
and I might spare your life.
وأستطيع أن أنقذ حياتك.
Li Yuanze.
لي يوانزي.
Do you think
هل تعتقد
this is still when Liu Zhen was alive?
هل كان هذا عندما كان ليو تشن على قيد الحياة؟
Jing has long since changed.
لقد تغير الجينغ منذ فترة طويلة.
Gentle as a crane,
لطيف كالطائر الكركي
a courteous gentleman?
رجل مهذب؟
Bah!
باه!
You're nothing more than
أنت لست أكثر من ذلك
a favored companion discarded by Princess Royal!
رفيق مفضل تم التخلي عنه من قبل الأميرة الملكية!
I'm afraid
انا خائف
your body
جسدك
has long been wrecked.
لقد تم تدميرها منذ فترة طويلة.
I'll tell you the truth.
سأخبرك الحقيقة.
Soon,
قريباً،
Princess Royal and General Gan
الأميرة الملكية والجنرال جان
will release me from here.
سيخرجني من هنا.
Why not kneel now,
لماذا لا تركع الآن؟
bang your head a few times, and beg me?
اضرب رأسك عدة مرات، وتوسل إلي؟
I can
أنا استطيع
put in a good word for you before Princess Royal,
ضع كلمة طيبة لك أمام الأميرة الملكية،
so that she
حتى انها
accepts you back.
يقبلك مرة أخرى.
How about that?
ماذا عن ذلك؟
Princess Royal is heading this way.
الأميرة الملكية تتجه نحو هذا الطريق.
Hear that?
هل سمعت ذلك؟
Princess Royal is here to save me.
الأميرة الملكية هنا لإنقاذي.
So what if I'm involved in bribery and corruption?
فماذا لو كنت متورطًا في الرشوة والفساد؟
Being on the right side is better than being a good official.
أن تكون على الجانب الأيمن أفضل من أن تكون مسؤولاً جيداً.
In the end,
في النهاية،
Ministry of Revenue is still mine...
وزارة الإيرادات لا تزال ملكي...
Li Yuanze, you've gone mad.
لي يوانزي، لقد جننت.
Executing court officials without orders
إعدام موظفي المحكمة دون أوامر
is a capital crime.
هي جريمة يعاقب عليها بالإعدام.
The late emperor gave me this imperial sword
لقد أعطاني الإمبراطور الراحل هذا السيف الإمبراطوري
that's perfect for removing corrupt officials
هذا مثالي لإزالة المسؤولين الفاسدين
and upholding court order.
وتأييد أمر المحكمة.
How could I fail His Majesty?
كيف يمكنني أن أخذل جلالته؟
Also,
أيضًا،
who said I killed you?
من قال لك أني قتلتك؟
Princess...
أميرة...
♪When we first met, moonlight rippled on the water♪
♪عندما التقينا لأول مرة، كان ضوء القمر يتلألأ على الماء♪
♪Your silhouette in dreams turning back with gentle eyes♪
♪ظلك في الأحلام تعود بعيون لطيفة♪
♪A trace upon my heart, a thought quietly hidden♪
♪أثر على قلبي، فكرة مخفية بهدوء♪
♪Words almost spoken, yet our story froze in time♪
♪الكلمات كادت أن تُقال، لكن قصتنا تجمدت في الزمن♪
♪Your gaze felt familiar♪
♪نظرتك كانت مألوفة♪
♪Etched into my heart, one tear swelling into a sea♪
♪محفورة في قلبي، دمعة واحدة تتضخم في البحر♪
♪How many times have we brushed past as our fates wavered?♪
♪كم مرة مررنا بمصيرنا عندما ترددت أقدارنا؟♪
♪Only to circle back into someone's open palm♪
♪فقط للعودة إلى راحة يد شخص ما المفتوحة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪That moment I saw you, spring awakened in me♪
♪في تلك اللحظة التي رأيتك فيها، أيقظ الربيع في داخلي♪
♪My heart suddenly becomes soft and tender♪
♪قلبي فجأة يصبح رقيقًا وحنونًا♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪Smiles and tears blurred everything in the past♪
♪الابتسامات والدموع طمس كل شيء في الماضي♪
♪The words were similar♪
♪الكلمات كانت متشابهة♪
♪With eyes closed, it felt like you were right beside me♪
♪مع عيون مغلقة، شعرت وكأنك كنت بجانبي مباشرة♪
♪After we part and meet again♪
♪بعد أن نفترق ونلتقي مرة أخرى♪
♪Your face had already changed♪
♪وجهك قد تغير بالفعل♪
♪Longing flowed and stirring waves of affection♪
♪تدفق الشوق وحرك أمواج المودة♪
♪If your words are clear♪
♪إذا كانت كلماتك واضحة♪
♪Like an image carved in the bones♪
♪مثل صورة منحوتة في العظام♪
♪It doesn't matter whose skin the soul hides underneath♪
♪لا يهم من يختبئ تحت جلد الروح♪